Guide to the Renew Media/Rockefeller Foundation Fellowships in New Media Art 2003-2004.
Renew Media/Rockefeller Foundation Fellowships in New Media Art 2003-2004
- Series II. Rockefeller New Media Fellowships 2004
  - Project Proposal: Christian Science Interactive Narratives (includes 2 copies of installation diagram), Snibbe, Scott Sona (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Video:
      - 2004 Sample Work (includes doc of installations "Deep Walls," "Compliant," "Boundary Functions," and website "It's Out")
  - Project Proposal: Publishing House, Temporary Services (Brett Bloom, Salem Collo-Julin, Marc Fischer) (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Zip Disk:
      - "Mobile Structures Resources"
    - Poster:
      - Binder Archives
      - Audio Relay
      - Publishing House (2 copies)
      - Packed and Ready (2 copies)
    - Book:
      - Prisoners' Inventions
    - Zine:
      - Drawn Out
      - Binder Archives: A Temporary Printing Ehibition
      - Binder Archives Exhibition Guide
      - Group Work
      - Into the Gravy, with G.W. Sok
      - Temporary Services Public Projects
      - Get Rid of Yourself
      - Audio Relay CD Inventory
      - Audio Relay
    - Website
      - Mobile Structure Resource
  - Project Proposal: The Active-Stimulation Feedback Platform (includes installation diagrams and sketches; project narrative and installation diagram include color illustrations), Vanouse, Paul (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Video:
      - Terminal Time
      - Paradise Reconfigured
      - The Relative Velocity Inscription Device
  - Project Proposal: Interactive Sampler, Vasulka, Steina (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Video:
      - 2004 Sample Work (includes doc of interactive violin and interactive installations)
    - Website
      - www.vasulka.org (see "Works by Steina" and "Video Works")
  - Project Proposal: The Brides of Frankenstein: Portraits of a Social Phenomenon, Wight, Gail (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Video:
      - Six recent Pieces (can't read?)
      - Crossing
      - Cabinet of Curiosities
      - 5 Work Samples
    - Slides:
      - 12 installation slides
    - Articles:
      - press/criticism
    - Catalog:
      - Gail Wight: The Evolution of Disarticulation
  - Project Proposal: Guests, Parasites and Symbionts: A Bio-Organism Based Art Installation, Wilson, Stephen (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - CD-ROM(s?): (Not Received)
      - CrimeZland
      - Is Anyone There
      - Protozoa Games
      - Transit Time
  - Project Proposal: Communicating Through Statues: A Proposal for a City of Strangers (includes project diagram), Wodiczko, Krzysztof (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Video:
      - From "The Hiroshima Projection"
      - From "The Tijuana Projection"
      - "Dis-Armor"
    - Slides:
      - 10 installation slides
    - Photos:
      - photo-quality prints of installation diagram
    - Articles:
      - press/criticism
- Series III. Rockefeller New Media Fellowships 2005
  - Project Proposal: "Six Walks", Anderson, Laurie (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Audio CD:
      - Work Samples (includes The Ugly One with the Jewels (1995), Bright Red Sampler (1994))
    - VHS:
      - Work Samples (includes Puppet Motel (demo of interactive CD-Rom), 1995)
  - Project Proposal: The Trial the Trail, Anstey, Josephine, and Dave Pape (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - VHS:
      - Work Samples (includes 2-8 minute clips of video doc of installations The Trial The Trail, 1st user test, PAAPAB (Pick an Avatar, Pick a Beat))
    - VHS:
      - Supplemental Material (includes 3-7 minute clips of video doc of installations The Thing Growing, Falling Over You)
  - Project Proposal: Super Plumber Guys Bootleg, Archangel, Corey (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - DVD:
      - Super Mario Clouds v2k3, 2004 (includes doc. of process, installation shots from exhibition and demo)
      - I Shot Andy Warhol (includes doc of installation)
  - Project Proposal: Path of the Dragon includes 3D visualization of proposed installation, Browning, Drew, and Annette Barbier (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - DVD:
      - Interactive Works (includes doc of 2004 performance River of Many Sides and Wave Harmonies (doc. of 2003 installation "Waiting in Line")
    - CD-Rom:
      - Home, 2000. (doc of VR version of "Home project") (needs Cosmo Player plug-in; internet links no longer active; PC OS preferred)
      - Homeland Insecurity (installation), 2003 (PC OS preferred) Extreme Measures (web art), 2004
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - Home
      - Homeland Insecurity
      - Extreme Measures
  - Project Proposal: No Name: Frequency and Repetition (or, how I managed to quiet my mind)(includes visualization and screen shots of proposed installation and images of works A-Maze (2001-2) and Symphasis (Simultaneous Appearances)), Bravo, Monika (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - CD-Rom:
      - (includes Quick Time movies of works A-Maze and Symphasis: Simultaneous Appearances)
    - Documents:
      - (Portfolio of color photocopies of critical press high-definition color images of works A-Maze, Symphasis: Simultaneous Appearances, and proposed project)
    - Catalog/Gallery Guide:
      - Monika Bravo: Itineraries, Ciocca Arte Contemporanea,Milan, Feb.-Apr. 2003
      - A-Maze, deChiara Gallery, NY, April-May 2002
      - Itineraries, Biblioteca Luis Angel Arango, Bogota, 2004
  - Project Proposal: Data Fictions (Walking and Weather Projection), Campbell, Jim (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - DVD:
      - 10 Works 1996-2003(includes documentation of installations and videos: Church on 5th Ave, 2001;Motion and Rest #5 and #2, 2002; Library, 2003; Self Portrait of Paul de Marinis, 2003; Last Day in the Beginning of March, 2003; Description of the Memory Works, 1994-1998; Photo of my Mother, 1996; Portrait of my Father, 1994-1995; Experiments in Touching Color, 1999; Involuntary Time, 2003; Weather Projection, 2005; Early Interactive Works 1988-1996)
  - Project Proposal: Remote Viewings (working title) includes installation diagram and guide to DVD portfolio, Cantanese, Paul (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - DVD:
      - DVD portfolio of selected work(includes one-minute video clips of: Medicinal Craft of Cephalopods (video documentation of digital Cornell box), 2004; Recollections of a Somnambulist (video documentation of digital Cornell box), 2004; A Short History of the Bezoar Stone (video documentation of digital Cornell box), 2004; Super Ichthyologist Advance (documentation of Multimedia Installation), 2003; Invisible Maps (excerpts from online project), 2001; Come Hither (doc. of multimedia installation), 2000; Fish Histories (excerpts from online project), 2000)
    - Essay:
      - "Evolution of a GBA Artist," to be published in Computer games and Art: Intersections and Interactions, ed. Grethe Mitchell and Andy Clarke. (Note: citation submitted as supplemental work sample, but no hard copy included in dossier; not yet published as of Dec. 2005)
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - Invisible Maps, 2001
      - paulcatanese.com, 1999, 2001-4
  - Project Proposal: An Interactive Map of Points of Interest in the United States, Coolidge, Matthew (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - Center for Land Use Interpretation Website (1994-present)
  - Project Proposal: Edgy Products, Csikszentmihalyi, Christopher (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - DVD(2 copies):
      - Media Interventions (includes doc of works History of Fictional Technologies (Natural Language Processor), DJ I, Robot, Skin and Control, and Afghan Explorer, as well as doc of projects produced at MIT’s Computing Culture Group 2003-4)
  - Project Proposal: ELIZA's Daughters includes 2 images of installation layout/floorplan, da Costa, Beatriz (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - VHS:
      - Cello, 2001(video doc. of robotic installation project)
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - www.beatrizdacosta.net
        documents works from 2000-4; Mac OS preferred
  - Project Proposal: Sonic Horizon(Includes diagrams and floorplans of proposed project and color photoprint of 2004 installation Errant Behaviors), Decker, Shawn (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - DVD:
      - Shawn Decker(includes doc of Scratch Studies (2001) doc of 2001 sound installation; The Night Sounds, doc of 2000 installation; Wire Field, 1997; Divided Circle, 1996; The Paradise, 2003; Klosterstrasse/Berlin, 2003; World-Wide Chocolate Heart, 2000; Music from the Well-Fed Abyss; Gerbera-Kiipula )
      - Errant Behaviors
  - Project Proposal: Code Zebra Synaptic Mapping, Diamond, Sara (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - CD-Rom:
      - VZ Collaboration-Presentation, 2003
        documents 2002-3 work on CodeZebra, including doc of installation at DEAF festival 2003) (2 copies; Windows OS preferred
      - CZ Demo Story Board, 2002
        2 copies; Windows OS preferred
    - DVD:
      - CZ website, 2004(documentation of Code Zebra website)
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - http://www.codezebra.net
        includes documentation, history, and rationale for project CodeZebra, 2004; Windows OS preferred
    - Book:
      - Sara Diamond: Memories Revisited, History Retold, by Jean Gagnon and Karen Knights.
        Published in conjunction with exhibition by same title at National Gallery of Canada, Ottawa, in March-May 1992. In English and French. 2 copies.
    - Print Materials
      - Packet of print materials(includes criticism and documentation of Code Zebra and other projects)
        b/w computer prints
      - Instructional Guide for The Lull Before the Storm, a 4-part video series on women's roles in British Columbia 1940-50.
      - Program: Outside/Inside! A Responsive Fashion and Costume Show, Banff New Media Institute, 2004
  - Project Proposal: Spectropia(includes diagram/floorplan of installation), Dove, Toni (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - DVD:
      - Toni Dove Work Samples(includes doc. of Artificial Changelings, 1998 (9 min); Spectropia Excerpts, (8.5 min))
  - Project Proposal: Toddler(includes visualization of proposed installation in use and dataflow/algorithm diagrams), Eshkar, Shelley (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - DVD:
      - Sample Works: Biped and Loops(includes video of performances Biped,1999, and Loops, 2001-5, and description of the creation process for Loops)
      - Pedestrian(with Paul Kaiser, complete DVD of animation, 2002)
    - CD-ROM:
      - Installation Slides: Eshkar Kaiser Steinberg(includes images of worksArrival, 2004; BIPED, 1999; Pedestrian, 2002; Immaterial/Ultramaterial, 2001)
  - Project Proposal: The Lighthouse(includes diagram and floorplan of proposed project and of installation M2, 1997), Farabough, Laura (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - VHS:
      - Laura Farabough-Work Sampler(includes documentation of T-Garden, 2001 (performance); Sauna 02, 2002 (public installation); Sauna prototype, 2000 (installation); M2, 1997 (installation))
      - Laura Farabough-Sponge
    - DVD:
      - Sponge-Laura's Edit(includes documentation of installations T-Garden, Sauna, Sauna Prototype, M2)
  - Project Proposal: memoria/memoir(includes floorplan of proposed installation), Flax, Carol (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - VHS:
      - Carol Flax: Visuals(includes 2-3 minute video documentation of 2 mothers, 2 daughters, 2 sisters, 2 brothers, 1 father (web art), 2003; Tuesday afternoon (web art), 2002; Journeys: 1900/2000 (interactive installation), 2000; Ex/Changing Families (interactive installation), 1997/1998)
    - CD-Rom:
      - Carol Flax: Supplemental Visuals, 2002(includes interactive documentation of ex/changing families, 1997/1998; journeys, 2000; 2 mothers, 2003; Tuesday afternoon, 2001; kyle (DVD installation), 2004; 2 mothers (dvd installation))
    - Catalog
      - Journeys 1900/2000: Carol Flax, for exhibition Voyages (per) Formed, Southeast Museum of Photography Oct 2000-Feb 2001
      - Voyages (per) Formed: exhibition catalogue, Southeast Museum of Photography Oct. 2000-Feb 2001.
  - Project Proposal: IM/UR II: Identity Exchange, Gharavi, Lance (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - DVD:
      - IM/UR, 2003(video doc of interactive performance)
      - Sound Zero, 2002(video doc of interactive digital video performance)
    - Article
      - "Dancing on the Emerald Table: (Mis)adventures in Esoterica and Performance," Text and Performance Quarterly 24 n. 3-4 (October 2004), 348-363. (Cited but not reproduced; not yet published at time of proposal submission.)
  - Project Proposal: An Eye for an Eye (includes special instructions for website use), Goldberg, Ken (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - VHS:
      - Ken Goldberg (includes doc of Power and Water, 1992; Mercury Project, 1994; Telegarden, 1995; Tele-Actor, 2001; Tele-Twister, 2003; Dislocation of Intimacy, 1998, 2004; Infiltrate, 2003; Ouija, 2000 )
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - Mori: An Internet-Based Earthwork
    - Catalog/Gallery Guide
      - Ken Goldberg: Matrix 186: Ouija 2000, Univeristy of California Berkeley Art Museum, Jan.-March 2000
      - Publicity for The Art, Technology, and Culture Colloquium, a group and series under the artist’s direction at UC Berkeley
    - Article
      - Excerpt from magazine Forefront (UC Berkeley College of Engineering) (includes article about Tele-Actor with two color photos)
  - Project Proposal:The Other Americans(includes detailed description of works documented in videotape and book), >Hackenberg, Sigrid (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - VHS:
      - Video and Sound Installations: 2001-2003 Sampler. 5 min.(includes documentation of: This Means YOU: Nazism, the Holocaust, and the Resistance 1933-1945 (video installation), 2003; Ich Heiße (my name is) Rosa Luxemburg (video and sound installation), 2001)
    - Print materials
      - This Means You: Nazism, the Holocaust, and the Resistance(installation guide; high-resolution prints on card stock; unbound)
      - Ich Heiße Rosa Luxemburg(installation guide; high-resolution prints in bound portfolio)
  - Project Proposal: The Tipping Point: Health Narratives from South End Artists includes diagram of installation "The Tipping Point Machine"and detailed description of works on "Five Projects" CD-Rom, Hall, Jennifer (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - CD-Rom:
      - Documentation: Five Projects 1995-2003(Windows OS preferred; includes Acupuncture for Temporal Fruit (robotic and interactive installation), 1999; Instrument for Medicated Terrain (robotic and interactive installation), 1999; Laboratory for Ephemeral Investigation (interactive video and robotic installation), 2002; Virtual Body/Physical Body (interactive installation and exploratory studio), 2000; epilepiform: REM 5 (3D interface and Sculpture Artifact), 2001 and 2003)
  - Project Proposal:: Electronic Crop Circle(includes visualization and plan of proposed project), Hirsch, Tad (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - DVD:
      - Institute for Applied Autonomy: “Bridging the Gap” (includes doc of works Contestational Robotics, StreetWriter, iSee, Little Brother Gets Busted, Principal’s Office)
  - Project Proposal: Mu Gu Gai Pan Over Rice Special #8(includes floorplans and diagrams for proposed installation (3 p. color print)), Ho, Raina (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - DVD:
      - Sample Work (Untitled: Demo Reel), approx. 12 minutes.(Includes doc. of Free Range Appliances in a Light Dill Sauce (interactive robotic installation), 2000; Free Range Appliances in a Light Dill Sauce, Swans Added (robotic performance); Modem (interactive video installation); PutFarm and PuttFarm II: MiniGolf (interactive public robotic performance); Flip (interactive installation); Stop Bugging Me, I'm Gonna Tell... (installation); Knit Magic Mad (installation); The Femme Fish Chart (installation/software))
    - CD-Rom:
      - Supplemental Work(offline version of the artist's website; includes detailed documentation of works on DVD as well as others)
  - Project Proposal: Chapter 3: Object of Desire(includes guided tour of website, "World of Awe"), Kanarek, Yael (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - World of Awe, the Travelers Journal, Chapters 1 and 2, 2000, 2002
        Windows OS preferred
    - Print materials
      - File:noplace399016.txt(excerpts from novel in progress; reproduced as part of proposal)
      - Love letter 685.2/9
  - Project Proposal: Visual Linguistics for a Multipurpose Toolkit(includes photographic documentation of projects Listen and Skipping (b/w photocopies)), Karam, David, and Gigi Obrecht (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - CD-Rom:
      - Listen, 1998(application; runs in Mac Classic OS, includes CD insert with instructions in many languages)
      - Skipping(software)
    - DVD:
      - Variations(video documentation of 2001 interactive musical installation)
    - Catalog
      - SFMOMA Experimental Design Award exhibition, 2001
  - Project Proposal: (Eye Contact: Observation as Interaction includes illustrations and diagrams of proposed installation (3 b/w pages) and descriptions of sample works), Levin, Golan (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - DVD:
      - Sample Work(includes 2-6 min. videos of Messa di Voce (performance) 2003; RE:MARK (interactive installation) 2002; Dialtones: A Telesymphony (interactive musical performance) 2001; Hidden Worlds of Noise and Voice (installation), 2002)
      - Ars Electronica: Active Score Music, includes software and full documentation of Scribble (performance) 2000 (28 min.)
      - Messa di Voce(full video documentation of performance)
    - Audio/CD-Rom:
      - Dialtones(recording of performance; includes video files)
    - CD-Rom:
      - Messa di Voce: Report and Documents Dialtones: Final Report
    - Portfolio
      - Still Images of Prior Works (1999-2004)(includes still images of installations/performances Audiovisual Environment Suite (1999-2000), Interactive Tables (2004), The Manual Input Sessions (2004), and The Secret Lives of Numbers (2002), in addition to works on main sample DVD.)
    - Book
      - Messa di Voce (2003)(documentation of performance, including development process, exhibition history, and reviews; includes DVD of performance and CD-Rom of related documents)
      - Dialtones (A Telesymphony), 2001(documentation of performance, including development process, exhibition history, and reviews; includes Audio CD of performance with video files and CD-Rom of related documents)
  - Project Proposal: The Story of Jennifer and Kevin McCoy(includes detailed descriptions of works on DVD), McCoy, Jennifer and Kevin (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - DVD:
      - Recent Projects: Jennifer and Kevin McCoy(includes 1-4 minute video clips of installations Soft Rains I (suburban horror), 2003; Soft Rains V (action scene), 2003; Soft Rains VII (european spa), 2003; Our Second Date, 2004)
      - Prints(3 photographs of installation How We Met, 2004)
    - Book
      - Learning to Watch: Jennifer and Kevin McCoy(includes documentation and criticism of installations and interview with the artists; in several languages)
  - Project Proposal: Jonny Spielt Jazz, Miller, Paul D (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - Errata Erratum, 2002:
    - CD
      - Standard Time, 2002(includes essays, audio tracks, Quick Time movie)
      - DJ Spooky: That Subliminal Kid: Jonny Spielt Jazz Audio Sketch
      - Rebirth of a Nation, 2004(demo of performance piece)
  - Project Proposal: Digital Stereoscope, Naimark, Michael (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - DVD:
      - Michael Naimark: 3 Projects 1993-2002(includes 1-6 min. video clips of See Banff! (3D immersive viewer); Be Now Here (multiple-person 3D immersive viewer); VR Webcam Studies)
  - Project Proposal: Untitled Story of Many, Navas, Eduardo (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - CD-Rom:
      - local copies of websites; internet connection required for links; Mac OS preferred(Includes sites: Net Art World 1.0, 2003; Diary of a Star, 2004-2005; Re_Cycled_Views, 2004; Plástico_2002_upDate, 2002; The Allegorical Impulse Part I, 2001; The Quixote, 2000; 9_11_2001 netMemorial, 2002)
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - Net Art World 1.0
        (local copies provided on CD-Rom)
      - Re_Cycled_Views
      - Plástico_2002_upDate
      - The Allegorical Impulse Part I
      - The Quixote
      - 9_11_2001 netMemorial
  - Project Proposal: Alien Monuments for Familiar Spaces(includes detailed descriptions of works documented on DVDs), Ortiz-Torres, Rubén (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - DVD:
      - The Garden of Earthly Delights, video/mechanical performance, 2002
      - 2nd Generation, installation/digital video, 2003
      - El Bodhisattva, installation/digital video, 2003
      - Mystery Monument in Canal St, webcam intervention, in progress
      - 3D Action Painting, computer animation, in progress
      - Rubén Oritz-Torres: The Texas Leaguer, computer animation
    - Catalog
      - Rubén Oritz-Torres: Behind the Garage Funk. Charles H. Scott Gallery, Vancouver, BC, Sept-Oct 2003.(Includes essay by John C. Welchman, "Ekeko to Mufflers: Rubén Oritz-Torres on Kustom, Kamoflage, and Kitch.")
      - Rubén Oritz-Torres: The Texas Leaguer, Glassell School of Art, Museum of Fine Arts, Houston, January-March 2004. (Includes essay by Valerie Loupe Olson, "Rubén Oritz-Torres: The Texas Leaguer," and DVD, Rubén Oritz-Torres: The Texas Leaguer.)
  - Project Proposal: Wandering Eye (includes diagrams, floorplans, and schematics of proposed installation), Osborn, Ed (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - VHS:
      - Ed Osborn: Sound Works (includes doc of installations Harvester, 2004; Particle Moves, 2003; Flying Machines, 2001)
    - Portfolio
      - Ed Osborn (color images and descriptions of 12 installations and videos, 1996-2004)
  - Project Proposal: To Make the Desert Bloom includes detailed descriptions of works in slides and on DVD, Parada, Esther (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - DVD:
      - Esther Parada(includes 4-5 min. video doc. of Canopy, installation, 1998, and When the Bough Breaks, installation, 2004)
    - CD-Rom:
      - "...To Make All Mankind Acquaintances."(Runs in Mac Classic environment)
    - Slides
      - 12 Slides(from series Past Recovery, 1979, Memory Warp 1980, and Jewels, Native Fruits, and Ragged Merchandise: Imaging Latin America, 2002)
    - Print materials
      - Promotional materials for When the Bough Breaks, Gallery 321, Chicago, Feb-March 2004(booklet, postcard)
      - Promotional materials/ gallery guides for Canopy: A Meditation on the Demise of the American Elm, Bunting Institute, Radcliffe College, June-July 1998(2 booklets)
      - Article by the artist "Taking Liberties: Digital Revision as Cultural Dialogue," published in Leonardo 26, no. 5, 1993, 445-450.
      - Original certificate of artist's sponsorship of two olive trees in Palestine
      - Quotations from news articles related to the project, 2 typed pages
  - Project Proposal: Pas de Deux, Rath, Alan (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - Documentation of Past Work (includes doc of 1986-1998 video and robotic sculptures Voyeur, Noise It All, Arecibo, Clamped, Clock, One track Minds, Pair, Inchworm, Robot Dance, Rover)
    - Catalog/Gallery Guide
      - Alan Rath, touring exhibit, 1991-2 (includes essay by Peter Boswell)
      - Alan Rath: New Sculpture, Galerie Hans Mayer, Düsseldorf, Oct.- Nov. 1992
      - Alan Rath, Hiroshima City Museum of Contemporary Art, May-June 1994
      - Alan Rath: Robotics, SITE Santa FE, Oct. 1998-Jan. 1999 (includes introduction by curator Louis Grachos)
  - Project Proposal: Processing includes detailed description of all work samples, Reas, Casey (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - Processing
        documentation and samples of work 2001-2004; local copy provided on CD-Rom:
      - GroupC Website
    - Mini-CD-Rom:
      - Processing software
      - GroupC Website and CD-Rom
    - CD-Rom:
      - X-Funs CD-Rom no. 13(includes samples of animations Structure 003A and Structure 003B)
    - Print materials
      - X-Funs Magazine(includes article about the artist, photos/screenshots of works, and X-Funs CD-Rom, above. Text in Chinese.)